spotifyjobs.com 2019-12-13

# Privacy Policy – Spotify Jobs

## Candidate Privacy Policy

Updated 18 June 2019.

### 1\. Introduction

Thanks for considering a job opportunity at Spotify. In order to apply for a job you need to provide us with some personal information about yourself.

The purpose of this Candidate Privacy Policy is to explain how we collect and process your personal data in the hiring process and give you information about the rights you have in relation to your personal data.

The data controller for the processing of your personal data in the hiring process is the Spotify entity in the country where the job you apply for is located.

### 2\. Your rights

You may be aware that the General Data Protection Regulation or “GDPR” gives certain rights to individuals in relation to their personal information. This includes the right to ask us for a copy of your personal data collected during the hiring process, to ask us to rectify or update your personal data, and to ask us to erase your personal data or stop using it for certain purposes. Under certain circumstances, you may also have the right to request data portability of your personal data in order to transmit the data to another data controller.

If you want to exercise any of your rights or if you have any questions about your privacy, your rights, or how to exercise them, please contact our Data Protection Officer by emailing [candidateprivacypolicy@spotify.com](mailto:candidateprivacypolicy@spotify.com). We will respond to your request within a reasonable period of time upon verification of your identity. While we hope that we can answer any questions that you may have, if you have unresolved concerns you also have the right to lodge a complaint with the Swedish Data Protection Authority (Datainspektionen) or your local Data Protection Authority.

.

### 3\. What personal data do we collect from you?

When you apply for a job at Spotify, the types of information we collect and process include, but are not limited to, the following categories:

  * Contact information – Your name, email address, postal address, phone number, city and country.
  * Background details – Your CV or resume, including cover letter, academic qualifications, work experience, transcripts, and/or similar.
  * Reference information and information received from background checks, including criminal records (if applicable).
  * Demographic information – Gender identity and date of birth. Additionally, for roles in US we may, only with your permission, collect and process sensitive and/or demographic information such as race, ethnicity, veteran status and information about citizenship and/or nationality for the purpose of understanding the demographics of our applicants and track the conversion rates of applications through the process to make sure that we have a non-discriminatory hiring process.
  * Interview information – Details from interviews and outcomes of any recruiting exercise you complete, including personality/reasoning ability tests.
  * Employment information – Information about the type of employment you are looking for or may be interested in, including current and required compensation, benefits and other job preferences.
  * Publicly available information – Profile information, academic qualifications and work experience from publicly available sources relevant for the hiring process, e.g. your LinkedIn profile.

### 4\. What do we use your personal data for?

We will use the information we collect about you for the following purposes:

  * To communicate with you throughout the hiring process

  * To update and keep your contact information, CV and/or other information accurate if you provide us with a new or updated version

  * To assess your qualifications, skills, and suitability

  * To consider you for, and inform you about other job opportunities (with your consent if required by applicable laws)

  * To verify your information and carry out reference checks

  * To prepare your employment agreement if you are offered a job at Spotify

  * To assist you with obtaining an immigration visa or work permit (if requested by you)

  * To comply with applicable laws, regulations, legal processes or enforceable governmental requests

In addition, we process your information (on an aggregated level) to perform analysis in order to understand, maintain and improve our hiring process.

### 5\. Sharing your personal data and transfer to other countries

We share your personal data globally with other companies in the Spotify Group in order to carry out the activities specified in this Policy. We may also transfer your personal data to third party service providers such as recruiting firms and providers of recruiting software.

Where personal data collected within the European Union and Switzerland is transferred to and processed by third parties located in a country outside of the European Union and Switzerland, Spotify shall ensure that the transfer of your personal data is carried out in accordance with applicable privacy laws and, in particular, that appropriate contractual, technical, and organizational measures are in place such as the Standard Contractual Clauses approved by the EU Commission.

6\. Data retention and deletion

If you are successful in your job application, the information we collect about you during the hiring process will become a part of your employment record and retained in accordance with our privacy policies for employee data.

If your application is unsuccessful, we retain your personal data for as long as necessary to comply with our legal obligations and resolve any disputes related to the hiring process. We may also, with your consent if required by applicable laws, retain your personal data for as long as allowed under applicable laws in order to consider you for future job opportunities at Spotify.

7\. What legal basis we have for processing your information

We collect and process information about you as necessary for our legitimate interest to assess fit for employment at Spotify and, if appropriate, enter into a contract of employment with you, and also to understand, maintain and improve our hiring process.

We may also seek your consent to process your personal data for specific reasons where necessary to comply with applicable laws. You have the right to withdraw such consent at any time by contacting us.

### 8\. Contact us

Thank you for reading our Candidate Privacy Policy. If you have any questions about this Policy, please contact our Data Protection Officer by emailing [candidateprivacypolicy@spotify.com](mailto:candidateprivacypolicy@spotify.com)
